

RAOA FARIA KARIM

Cloud Support Engineer Computer Science Graduate

ABOUT ME

I graduated from University of Technology Malaysia (UTM) with a major in Computer Science, specializing in Computer Networks & Security. Currently, I work as a Cloud Support Engineer at Wavelet Solutions Sdn. Bhd. and have previous experiences as a Network Engineer Intern and a Security Analyst Intern.

OBJECTIVE

I am driven to continue my education to further enhance my knowledge and expand my research horizons. Pursuing a PhD in Computer Science will enable me to achieve this goal. I am eager to embrace new challenges, collaborate with others professionally, and achieve my career goal of becoming an exceptional researcher.

CONTACT



+60176957142 (WhatsApp)



karim1998@graduate.utm.my



linkedin.com/in/raoa-faria-karim



https://raoafariakarim.github.io/

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE 2018-2023 (COMPUTER NETWORKS & SECURITY)

University of Technology Malaysia CGPA: 3.39/4.00 (Dean's List Awards)

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE 2015-2017

Govt. Hazi Mohammad Mohsin College, Chattogram, Bangladesh. GPA: 4.83/5.00

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE 2005-2015

Ispahani Public School and College, Chattogram, Bangladesh. GPA: 5.00/5.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

CLOUD SUPPORT ENGINEER

May 2023 - Present

Wavelet Solutions Sdn Bdn Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Providing Technical Support for AWS environment.
- Working with the ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) and MIS (Management Information Systems) Team.
- Doing Incident Management & Infrastructure Management
- · Troubleshooting and Debugging.

SECURITY ANALYST INTERN

November 2022 - January 2023

Firmus Sdn Bhd, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Carried out Network Penetration Testing using Nmap tool.
- Performed Web application Penetration Testing using tools like Nessus, burp suit and Mobile Penetration Testing.
- Wrote detailed reports on vulnerability assessment & researching on security services.

NETWORK ENGINEER INTERN

October 2021 -February 2022

Dotlines Sdn Bhd, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Created iptables using Bash Scripting for Blacklisting/ Whitelisting.
- Packet Capturing and Analysis, DNS web filtering.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT August 2020 - September 2021

Final Year Project Lab, UTM, Johor

· Worked under Dr. Johan Bin Mohamad Sharif.

- Assisted fellow students in developing their projects under his guidance.
- Explored Moving Target Defense (MTD) and Deception techniques.
- Developed a project on ad hoc networks, showcasing exceptional research skills.
- Assisted juniors in formatting reports using Latex software.

ACHIEVEMENTS

DEAN'S LIST AWARDS

- Dean's List Award (2020/2021-2)
- Dean's List Award (2021/2022-1)
- Dean's List Award (2021/2022-2)

AIESEC Virtual Volunteer (AIESEC)

- Conducted a workshop on Cyber Security.
- Resolved problems, improved operations, and provided exceptional service.
- Maintained energy and enthusiasm in the fast paced environment.
- Completed all paperwork, recognizing any problem and solving it.

Hult Prize Participant (Teamwork)

- Gathered entrepreneural experience based on Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).
- Developed an idea of biodegradable containers which will serve the environment.
- Worked with UTM XCITE.

CERTIFICATIONS

CCNA CERTIFICATIONS

- CCNA: Introduction to Networks
- CCNA: Switching, Routing & Wireless Essentials
- IoT Fundamentals: Connecting Things
- CCNA: Enterprise Networking, Security, and Automation

TRAININGS

MICROSOFT MALAYSIA STUDENT ACCELERATOR (MMSA) PROGRAM

Got selected as a participant in the inaugural batch of the program in 2020. This intensive 6-month program focused on advanced analytics & AI, Azure & Cloud Fundamentals, and Web Apps & APIs.

Big Query Basics for Data Analytics (Google Cloud Jam)

Learnt to query terabytes and terabytes of data without the need for any infrastructure or a database administrator.

PROJECTS

UTM Industrial Training System (Final Year Project)

Developed an android mobile application system using Flutter to build a bridge between recruiters and students for internships. I used Data Scraping Technology to advance the search procedure.

Grading System (Storing the data into linkedlist and binary tree)

Led the team utilizing linked lists and binary trees to store the data efficiently while developing a grading system for our Data Structure & Algorithm course.

Security ATM Transaction System

Mitigated SQL Injection and XSS vulnerabilities while building ATM transaction system with my team.

AI in Radiology (Automated Image Analysis and Diagnosis)

Submitted a research report on the scopes of automated image analysis and diagnosis which can also assist radiologists by providing decision support, quantitative measurements, and prognostic insights with the help of AI.

University Announcement System with Microsoft Power Apps

Built an announcement system using Microsoft Power Apps, which served as the final project in Microsoft Malaysia Student Accelerator Program (MMSA).

SKILLS

- Security Analysis
- Cryptography
- Data Analysis
- Secure Systems Design
- UX and UI Design
- AWS Cloud Architecture
- Technical Writing
- Programming Language:
 - Dart Language
 - · C++
 - Javascript
 - PHP
 - Python
 - R Programming